<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A Testimony for the man, Christ Jesus repelling the poyson &amp; fallacy of William Haworth's pretended antidote against the Quakers / from the people of [sic] Quakers at Hertford.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1676</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 35 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 9 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A64454</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing T811</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R9910</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">13770230</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 13770230</idno>
            <idno type="VID">101741</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A64454)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 101741)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 852:44)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A Testimony for the man, Christ Jesus repelling the poyson &amp; fallacy of William Haworth's pretended antidote against the Quakers / from the people of [sic] Quakers at Hertford.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>16 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1676.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Place of publication from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Haworth, William. --  Antidote against that poysonous and fundamental errour of the Quakers.</term>
               <term>Jesus Christ --  Humanity --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Society of Friends --  Doctrines.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-08</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-02</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-02</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:101741:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:101741:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A TESTIMONY For the MAN Chriſt Jeſus, REPELLING The POYSON &amp; FALLACY of <hi>William Haworth</hi>'s pretended Antidote againſt the Quakers.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>From the People of</hi> QUAKERS <hi>at</hi> HERTFORD.</p>
            <q>
               <bibl>Jer. 23. 32.</bibl> And they cauſe my People to Err, by their Lyes and by their Lightneſs.</q>
            <p>Printed in the Year, 1676.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:101741:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:101741:2"/>
            <head>A TESTIMONY For the Man Chriſt Jeſus, &amp;c.</head>
            <p>UPon peruſal of <hi>William Haworth</hi>'s late Pamphlet, we find that it conſiſts chiefly of Matter of Charge, ag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gravated by reviling, and of Anſwers to ſome Obje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctions of his own framing, to render the <hi>Quakers infamous and odious.</hi> In both which we ſhall very briefly and perſpicuouſly manifeſt his groſs Abuſe and <hi>Fallacy.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>His Title is, <hi>An Antidote againſt that Poyſonous and Funda<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mental Error of the</hi> Quakers.</p>
            <p>This makes a huge Bluſter; but what's that <hi>Poyſonous and fundamental Error</hi> he charges the <hi>Quakers</hi> with?</p>
            <p>It is no leſs then <hi>Denying the ſame Numerical, True &amp; Real Manhood of Jeſus Chriſt in Heaven, a place remote from the earth.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>A ſad Charge! that makes an hideous Out-cry: But the <hi>Quakers</hi> utterly deny the Matter charged, not doubting but their Credit will go as far at leaſt as <hi>Will Haworth's,</hi> and farther then his Reviling to Aggravate in theſe words, viz. <hi>That we ſhould live to ſee the Day wherein ſo many Thouſands pretending Chriſtianity in this Nation, ſhould be ſo brazen-foreheaded, as to diſown</hi> Jeſus <hi>of</hi> Nazareth <hi>to be the</hi> Meſſiah; <hi>yet ſo it is, O Tempora! O Mores</hi>! and farther adds, <hi>Theſe Damnable De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>luſions — The man Chriſt is ſtruck at by ungodly Seducers, &amp;c.</hi> Epiſtle. <hi>That the</hi> Quakers <hi>may not deceive you by their Juggles,</hi> p. 3. <hi>Jeſuitical Inſinuations,</hi> p. 20. <hi>How can the</hi> Quakers <hi>be</hi> Chriſtians? p. 15.</p>
            <p>Had <hi>Will. Haworth</hi> ſeriouſly conſidered that <hi>no Revilers ſhall
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:101741:3"/>
inherit the Kingdom of God,</hi> I Cor. 6. 10. and that <hi>all Lyars muſt have their Portion in the Lake,</hi> he would have forborn this kind of treating us. Here is a two fold Charge, firſt, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nying the ſame true and real Manhood of Jeſus Chriſt in Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven, &amp;c. 2dly, Diſowning Jeſus of <hi>Nazareth</hi> to be the Meſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiah, with his aggravating Exclamations againſt the <hi>Quakers,</hi> both which are not only utterly denyed by the <hi>Quakers,</hi> but alſo the ſaid <hi>W. Haworth</hi> therein teſtified againſt, as a <hi>diſingenuous Perſon,</hi> not ſo much as citing the <hi>Quakers</hi> words at the <hi>Diſpute</hi> he mentions; but from his own <hi>prejudiced Conceptions,</hi> writes againſt us that wherein he is a manifeſt Slanderer and Forger, and ſo led by a Lying Spirit: For, what's his Proof or Quota<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion for ſuch his Charge of denying the <hi>real Manhood of Jeſus Chriſt,</hi> or <hi>him to be the Meſſiah?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>To make out this, he tells his <hi>Much Honoured Friend Sr. John Hartop,</hi> in theſe plain words, viz. <hi>Sr. That which gave the Occaſion of my Thoughts, pitching upon this ſubject matter, viz. Chriſt's Manhood in Heaven, was that Diſpute, between Mr.</hi> Hicks <hi>and Mr.</hi> Penn, <hi>at</hi> London <hi>concerning the ſame, I being there preſent, am ſatisfied by the</hi> Quakers <hi>fallacious Mannage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of that Diſcourſe, that they Deny the ſame Numerical, True and Real Manhood of Chriſt in Heaven, &amp;c.</hi> See now his pretended Proof of his great Charge, is his own meer Opi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nion, from that Diſpute; but whether herein he has not appa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rently acted the part of a <hi>Forger,</hi> let all that impartially read the <hi>Account</hi> 
               <note n="‖" place="margin">Which was publiſhed by <hi>Will. Mead, Io. Oſgood, will. Shewen, Ed. Man, Sa. Newton, Ja. Claypool &amp; Will. Welch,</hi> who with many hundreds more can teſtifie to the Truth thereof, and againſt <hi>Will. Haworth</hi>'s groſs Abuſe and Fallacy.</note> of that ſaid Diſpute between the <hi>Quakers</hi> and <hi>Bap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſts</hi> at <hi>Barbican</hi> judge. See p. 26 of the <hi>Account,</hi> where <hi>W. Penn</hi> ſpeaks in the Name or Perſon of the <hi>Quakers</hi> thus, viz. <hi>We do believe the Man Chriſt Jeſus to be glorified in Heaven— We do believe that holy Manhood to be in Heavenly Glory, &amp;c.</hi> See now, how far the <hi>Quakers</hi> are from denying the <hi>true &amp; real Manhood of Chriſt in Heaven,</hi> or diſowning <hi>Jeſus of Nazareth
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:101741:3"/>
to be the Meſſiah:</hi> And therefore, how guilty this Prieſt is of <hi>Forgery</hi> and manifeſt <hi>Slander</hi> herein? The matter which he ſaith we deny, being ſo openly by us confeſt at the ſame Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pute aforeſaid, only his artificial Term <hi>[Numerical]</hi> and his Addition of <hi>A PLACE REMOTE FROM THE EARTH</hi> were not the Terms of the Queſtion at that Diſpute, he hath framed theſe ſince; neither can we yet underſtand, what Weight or Plainneſs his Logical Term <hi>[Numerical]</hi> addeth to <hi>the ſame True and real Manhood of Chriſt,</hi> which we ſo plainly confeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing, <hi>We do believe the Man Chriſt Ieſus to be glorified in Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven,</hi> was by judicious Hearers judged a ſufficient Anſwer to the Queſtion, as then ſtated.</p>
            <p>And as to his Addition of <hi>[Place remote from the Earth]</hi> we further add and confeſs, that the ſame <hi>MAN</hi> Chriſt Je<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſus that ſuffered, and was put to Death in the Fleſh, and rai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed from the Dead by the mighty Power of God, <hi>aſcended</hi> in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to Heaven, God's Dwelling place, aſcended both as to a Change of Place &amp; State of Glory; he is highly exalted in Pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er and Authority, Angels, Authorities and Powers being made ſubject unto him, 1 <hi>et.</hi> 3. 22. <hi>Being the Head of his Body the Church, the Beginning, the firſt born from the dead, that</hi> in all things <hi>he might have the Preeminence,</hi> Col. 1. 17. <hi>The God of our Father raiſed up Jeſus, whom ye ſlew and hanged on a Tree, him hath God exalted with his right Hand to be a Prince and a S. A. VIOUR, to give Repentance to</hi> Iſrael, <hi>and Forgiveneſs of Sins,</hi> Acts 5, 30, 31. So that the Power and Authority where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in he is exalted, is both to be a Prince and a Saviour, and to give Gifts, and to be Head of his Body the Church, in all Things to have the Preeminence, and therefore this Exaltati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, and Power was not that he might remain in a Place remote and ſeparate from his Body the Church, which he is the Head of; for that were to keep the Body and Head aſſunder, ſo far remote from each other, and then how ſhould it be a Living Body, <hi>or united to him?</hi> page 10. whereas the Son of God had Power not only to aſcend far above all Heavens, but alſo to deſcend, at his Pleaſure to come again as he promiſed, <hi>to be with his Diſciples alway to the End, having all Power in Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven and in Earth given to him,</hi> Mat. 28. John 14.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="6" facs="tcp:101741:4"/>
Yet that Jeſus Chriſt is now a true &amp; real Man in the Heavens is not deayed by the <hi>Quakers,</hi> as this Oppoſer moſt falſly ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuſeth them page 2: but his Concluſion, that therefore <hi>Jeſus Chriſt is not here on Earth as he is Man, but as to his Manhood only in Heaven a Place remote from us,</hi> page 2, 3. whileſt he thus defines his Manhood, viz. <hi>a Conſiſting of Soul and Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy, and that this Soul is in Heaven, which he confeſſeth to be his Spirit, from</hi> Luke 23. 46.</p>
            <p>By this Man's Limitation Jeſus Chriſt (not only as to his bodily Preſence, but alſo as to his Spiritual) is not here on Earth in his Church: And yet in page 5. he confeſſeth, <hi>That Chriſt is in the Saints by his Spirit,</hi> and <hi>that Chriſt was certainly with</hi> Paul, <hi>as to his Spirit,</hi> where he ſaid, <hi>The Lord ſtood by me,</hi> 2 Tim. 4. 17. And this is the very thing the <hi>Quakers</hi> plead for, viz. <hi>Chriſt's Spiritual Preſence with his Saints.</hi> See how the Man is confounded, after he has gone about to limit the <hi>Man Chriſt Ieſus wholely in Body, Soul and Spirit to a remote Place from his Saints or Church here on Earth;</hi> yet is made to confeſs to this Truth, viz. <hi>That Chriſt is in his Saints by his Spirit:</hi> If he ſayes, He means only <hi>as God, who is im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>menſe, and as to his Preſence every where:</hi> This were to tell us, <hi>He does not mean any thing of the Man Chriſt is in his Saints on Earth,</hi> when he confeſſeth, <hi>that by his Spirit he is in the Saints, and yet his Spirit is an Eſſential Part of the Man Chriſt;</hi> let him reconcile himſelf herein if he can, inſtead of any further Reviling and Abuſing the <hi>Quakers,</hi> as <hi>Ungodly, Seducers, diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>owning Ieſus of</hi> Nazareth <hi>to be the Meſſiah, and denying him to be a real and true Man;</hi> both which are abominable Slanders: ſeeing they own him to be both God and Man in Union inſepa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable, <hi>the Father and Son one, the Father in the Son, and the Son in the Father; he that ſeeth the Son, ſeeth the Father alſo.</hi> We are not only accuſed with denying, <hi>where the Man Chriſt Ieſus is aſcended into Heaven,</hi> but alſo <hi>what he is,</hi> to wit, <hi>the Meſſiah, if a true real Man;</hi> and yet he faith, <hi>They may grant a Manhood, and yet deny the Fleſh in which he was to be in Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>See how uncertain and doubtful this Man is in his Charge, <hi>that they may deny his Manhood, and yet grant a Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hood.</hi>
               <pb n="7" facs="tcp:101741:4"/>
Whereas we have alway believed and owned the Man Chriſt Jeſus, according to the plain Hiſtory of him in holy Scripture, as well as in the Myſtery; as name<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, <hi>That he was miraculouſly conceived by the Holy Ghoſt over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhadowing the Virgin</hi> Mary; <hi>that he lived an innocent and ſinleſs Life; preacht powerfully; wrought Miracles; was Crucified and put to Death, as concerning the Fleſh; Buried, and Roſe again the third day, according to the Scriptures; and was ſeen of his Diſciples and many Brethren after he aroſe:</hi> ſee 1 Cor. 15. 3, 4, 5, 6. and that <hi>the ſame Body that was put to Death, was raiſed by the Power of God:</hi> And this was not only <hi>an Appear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance, or Spectrum in the Shape of a man,</hi> as <hi>W. H.</hi> ſaith <hi>ſome have held:</hi> nor yet a meer <hi>phantaſtical Body or Apparition,</hi> but a <hi>real Body, really ſeen both before and after his Reſurrection, and at his Aſcenſion alſo; while he bleſſed them he was parted from them, and carried up into Heaven,</hi> Luk. 24. 50, 51. <hi>And while they beheld, he was taken up, and a Cloud received him out of their Sight,</hi> Acts 1. 9, 10. So we confeſs the ſame Man Chriſt, not only to be ſtill in being, but alſo Glorified, &amp; his Body to be <hi>a glorious, heavenly and ſpiritual Body.</hi> And as to his being Man; <hi>We have one Mediator between God and Men, even the</hi> Man <hi>Chriſt Jeſus,</hi> 1 Tim. 2. 5. And <hi>God will judge the World in Righ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teouſneſs, by that</hi> Man <hi>whom he hath ordained, whom he hath raiſed from the Dead,</hi> Acts 17. 31. Again, <hi>This</hi> Man, <hi>after he had offered up one Sacrifice for Sins, forever ſate down on the Right Hand of God,</hi> Hebrews 10. 12, And <hi>ſince by man came Death by</hi> Man <hi>alſo came the Reſurrection of the Dead; the firſt man is of the Earth, earthly; the ſecond</hi> Man <hi>is the Lord from Heaven.</hi> So that this Man Chriſt did nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther vaniſh nor periſh in anything eſſential to him either as to his Soul, Spirit or Body <note n="‖" place="margin">As for <hi>W. H's</hi> taking advantage upon a private Diſcourſe, with his Neighbour <hi>W. B.</hi> (whether he truly ſtates it or not is queſtionable) and thence to notifie him and the <hi>Quakers</hi> in print ſhews a peeviſh, ereeping, in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſinuating ſpirit in him, that ſeeks oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caſions againſt his neighbours to quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rel, which is not the way to convince or gain upon their Conſcience, to be ſure, of under any Miſtake.</note> but is highly exalted and glorified, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:101741:5"/>
made higher then the Heavens, <hi>Heb.</hi> 7. 26. being ſate down on the right Hand of the Majeſty on high, <hi>Heb.</hi> 1. 3. who is ſet on the right Hand of the Throne of the Majeſty in the Heavens, <hi>Heb.</hi> 7. 1. And Jeſus ſaid, <hi>Ye ſhall ſee the Son of Man ſitting on the right Hand of the Power</hi> (that is, the Power of God) <hi>and coming in the Clouds of Heaven,</hi> Mark 14. 62. Luke 22. 69.</p>
            <p>But now the Difference between us and our Adverſary <hi>W. Haworth</hi> lies here, if he ſtill ſhall argue, that <hi>becauſe this glo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rious and Heavenly Man Jeſus Chr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſt is thus exalted at the Right Hand of the Power and Majeſty of God on high, that therefore he is not here on Earth, or in his Saints, either as to his Soul or Spirit,</hi> We cannot own ſuch a Limitation of Chriſt's or God's Right Hand of Power, thus to look on them as ſo far remote and ſeparate from us, as this Man doth, wherein he ſeems ſomewhat to reſemble that carnal Opinion of thoſe called, <hi>Anthropomorphites,</hi> who miſtaking that Say<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, <hi>Let us make Man in our own Image,</hi> held that <hi>God was like unto Man in Form and Shape;</hi> and the like doth <hi>Muggle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton</hi> and his Diſciples now, that <hi>God is of the ſtature and Bigneſs of a Man, and the Man Chriſt at his Right Hand, as ſuch.</hi> And thus carnally and blaſphemouſly have ſome Men gone a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout to limit the Infinite and Omnipotent God, looking only literally upon him, and his Right Hand of Power, and then how were his People of old ſaved or upheld by his right Hand? Surely God's Right Hand is where he is, not confined or limi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted from his Saints, who are ſuſtained and preſerved thereby. It's true that Jeſus Chriſt ſaid, <hi>I go to prepare a Place for you,</hi> John 14. 2, 3 <hi>I am no more in the World, but theſe are in the World, I come to thee holy Father,</hi> John 17. Now this ſaith <hi>W. H. muſt needs be as to his Manhood; for the Father and he were one, as to his Godhead in Eſſence, and ſo he was with the Father from Eter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nity,</hi> John 1. 1. Prov. 8. 22. 30.</p>
            <p>And who denyes this? did we ever deny that the Man Chriſt the Son of God went unto the Father, who is in Heaven, when he aſcended? but doth it then follow, that Jeſus Chriſt is ſo contained and limited there, in a remote Place from his Church, as not to be here on Earth in his Saints, but only <hi>in ſuch
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:101741:5"/>
Places where we read, of Jeſus Chriſt by Name appearing that either they ſaw him, the Heavens being opened, or it was in Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taſie,</hi> as <hi>W. Haworth</hi> ſaith, page 4.</p>
            <p>If his being aſcended into Heaven hinders him from being on Earth, why not his aſcending <hi>far above all Heavens,</hi> from being in Heaven; but in the very ſame Place before quoted <hi>John</hi> 14. 2, 3. the ſame <hi>Man Chriſt</hi> that ſaid, <hi>I go to prepare a Place for you,</hi> ſaid alſo, <hi>If I go and prepare a Place for you, I will come again and receive you unto my ſelf, that where I am there ye may be alſo,</hi> &amp; verſe 18. <hi>I will not leave you comfortleſs, I will come to you,</hi> and ver. 19. <hi>Yet a little while and the World ſeeth me no more, but ye ſee me; becauſe I live, ye ſhall live alſo.</hi> And ver<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>e 20. <hi>At that Day ye ſhall know that I am in my Father, and ye in me, &amp; I in you.</hi> And was not this the Man Chriſt Jeſus that ſpake theſe things, who alſo ſaid, <hi>No Man hath aſcended up to Heaven, but he which came down from Heaven, even the</hi> Son of Man, <hi>which is in Heaven</hi> John 3. 13. Now if it be ſaid that the Son of man was ſpiritually in Heaven, when on Earth, then may it not as well be ſaid, that the Son of man is ſpiritually on Earth in his Saints when in Heaven, ſeeing all Power in Heaven and in Earth is given to the Son? And the Father hath given him Power over all Fleſh, that he ſhould give Eternal Life, to as many as the Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther hath given him, <hi>John</hi> 17. 2. <hi>He is aſcended far above all Heavens<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> that he might fill all things</hi> Epheſ. 4. 10. And what Place went he to prepare for his? but ſuch a Place in and with himſelf, as that where he is, there they might be alſo, John 14. 3. where the Saints were made to ſit together in the Heavenly Places in Chriſt Jeſus. And our Converſation is in Heaven, from whence alſo we look for a Saviour, the Lord Jeſus Chriſt, <hi>Phil.</hi> 3. 20. And of his coming again the Apoſtles had ſignal Evidences who <hi>BY HIM</hi> wrought Miracles, even by <hi>HIM</hi> whom the Men of <hi>Iſrael</hi> delivered up and denyed in the Preſence of <hi>Pilate; By this HOLY ONE, this Prince of Life,</hi> whom God raiſed from the dead, were the Lame healed, <hi>Acts</hi> 3. 11, 16. &amp; chap. 4 10 <hi>By the Name of Jeſus Chriſt of</hi> Nazareth, <hi>whom ye crucified, whom God raiſed from the dead, even by HIM doth this man ſtand before you whole</hi> And ver
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:101741:6"/>
30. <hi>That Signs and Wonders may be done by the Name of thy holy Child Jeſus whom thou haſt anointed.</hi> Ver 17. <hi>This Ieſus hath God raiſed up, whereof we are all Witneſſes,</hi> Acts 2. 32. <hi>Therefore being by the Right Hand of God exalted, and having received of the Father the Promiſe of the holy Ghoſt, he hath ſhed forth this which ye now ſee and hear,</hi> ver. 33. And Acts 5. 32. <hi>Him hath God exalted with his Right Hand to be a Prince and a Saviour, for to give Repentance to</hi> Iſrael, <hi>and Forgiveneſs of Sins: God having raiſed up his Son Jeſus,</hi> SENT HIM to bleſs you, <hi>in turning away every one of you from his Iniquities,</hi> Acts 3. 26.</p>
            <p>Now having thus plainly confeſſed to the Reſurrection, Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>altation &amp; Work of the ſame Ieſus of <hi>Nazareth</hi> that was cru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cified, let us briefly take Notice of what <hi>W. H.</hi> ſaith about <hi>Stephen</hi> and <hi>Paul</hi>'s ſeeing of Jeſus Chriſt, and of the <hi>Properties of his Manhood.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>After he hath told us, <hi>they ſaw him with their CARNAL EYES when he was taken up into Heaven,</hi> on Acts 1. 11. he cites <hi>Acts</hi> 7. 56. <hi>Behold I ſee the Heavens opened,</hi> and ſaith, Ste<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phen's <hi>fight was ſtrengthned after a wonderful miraculous Way, ſo that he pierced to the very Heavenly Glory with his Eye, this is more then what was Natural no Doubt; for the other that ſtood by ſaw nothing, but he ſaw as much of the Heavenly Glory, as he could bear,</hi> page 4. and in page 6. concerning the Glorious Body of Chriſt, he ſaith, <hi>It is NOW ſince the Aſcenſion the Object of Senſe,</hi> it hath been ſeen with the Bodily Eye, <hi>and may be ſeen,</hi> Stephen <hi>its Evident ſaw the Body of Chriſt,</hi> and Paal <hi>ſaw him with his BODILY EYE,</hi> 
               <note n="*" place="margin">Doth the Scripture ſay ſo, for that cited doth not.</note> 1 Cor. 15. 8. <hi>laſt of all I ſaw him.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>That <hi>Stephen</hi> ſaw the Heavens opened, and Jeſus ſtanding at the right hand of God, is true, but that he ſaw him then with his carnal or bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dily Eyes, when this was more then what was Natural, doth not appear to be ſound or congru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous Doctrine, eſpecially ſince <hi>W. H.</hi> confeſſeth on <hi>Epheſ.</hi> 4. 10. <hi>That therefore Chriſt as to his Manhood is not in any of theſe viſible Heavens; for he paſſed through theſe, and went into that INVISIBLE moſt ſupream Heaven, the Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:101741:6"/>
of Heavens, far above the other Heavens,</hi> Pſal. 68. <hi>He aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cended on high far above all Heavens,</hi> that is <hi>all heavenly Pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers of Angelical Nature and Perfection, he is above them,</hi> pag. 8. Whereas the Ground of <hi>Stephen</hi>'s ſeeing the Heavens open<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, and Jeſus on the right hand of God was on his <hi>being full of the holy Ghoſt,</hi> and not on his Carnal or Bodily Eyes, he be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing FULL OF THE HOLY GHOST looked up ſtedfaſtly into heaven, and ſaw the GLORY OF GOD, and Jeſus ſtanding on the Right Hand of God, and ſaid, <hi>Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold I ſee the Heavens opened, and the Son of Man ſtanding on the right hand of God,</hi> Acts 7. 55, 56. And likewiſe when <hi>John</hi> was in the Spirit on the Lord's Day, he ſaw <hi>the ſeven Golden Candleſticks, and in the midſt thereof One like unto the Son of man,</hi> &amp;c. Rev. 1. 12, 13. which ſeven Candleſticks, were the ſeven Churches of <hi>Aſia,</hi> that he wrote unto (which ſurely were then upon Earth) But to Place all this ſight upon carnal and bodily Eyes, is all one as if he ſhould tell us that <hi>Ste<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phen</hi> with his carnal and bodily Eyes ſaw the inviſible and ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pream Heaven opened, yea, and that with the ſame carnal or bodily Eyes he ſaw the GLORY of God alſo (for its ſaid, he ſaw the <hi>Glory of God)</hi> and Jeſus ſtanding on the right hand of God, and this renders both the Glory of God, and his right hand alſo, obvious and viſible to the carnal Eyes; you may ſee what mean and carnal Thoughts this man hath of God, and Chriſt the Glory of God.</p>
            <p>Whereas in page 6. <hi>William Haworth</hi> ſaith, concerning the Manhood or Body of Chriſt, <hi>It hath the ſame Form and Figure that it had when here upon Earth, elſe how could the Diſciples know him after the Reſurrection,</hi> and yet in the ſame page ſaith, <hi>It is a very GLORIOUS Body,</hi> PHIl. 3. <hi>Like unto his glorious Body. How gloriouſly it is repreſented, and painted out to us by</hi> Daniel, <hi>and</hi> John <hi>in the Revelations, more Bright then a Thouſand Suns.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſw.</hi> Is it ſo? How then hath it the ſame Form and Figure it had when here upon Earth? Or how is it ſeen with carnal Eyes, if ſo glorious and in the inviſible and moſt ſuppeam Heaven? And was it thus bright and glorious, more then a
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:101741:7"/>
Thouſand Suns when here upon Earth ſubject to Suffering; ſurely this man intrudes into that which he hath not ſeen.</p>
            <p>Was the Body of Chriſt while upon Earth in that State, ſo glorious as now <hi>[That is more bright then a Thouſand Suns, when he was apprehended, crowned with Thorns and condemned to dy upon the Croſs?]</hi> If ſo, wh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>re it's ſaid in that Place cited, <hi>Phil.</hi> 3. 21. <hi>Who ſhall change our v<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>le Body, that it may be faſhioned like unto his glorious Body;</hi> this is only to be underſtood, that our Body ſhall be faſhioned like to the Body of Chriſt, when upon Earth, wherein he was made like to his Brethren, and that is as good Senſe as to ſay, <hi>we ſhall be faſhioned like unto what we are:</hi> Where then is the Change? But if we ſhall be chan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged, as to our low Body, and be faſhioned into a glorious and ſpiritual State, then is Chriſt, as to his Body, changed or tranſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lated into a far more glorious State, then what it had upon Earth.</p>
            <p>But this man's concluding, <hi>That the Diſciples knew him af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter his Reſurrection, becauſe his Manhood had the ſame Form and Figure that it had before.</hi> In this he talks like one ignorant of the Scriptures; for after his Reſurrection he appeared in divers Forms, as, <hi>After that he appeared unto two of them in another Form,</hi> Mark 16. 12. <hi>Mary Magdalen</hi> ſuppoſed him to have been the Gardiner, <hi>John</hi> 20. 14, 15. And ſometimes he was unknown, and doubted of by his Diſciples, <hi>Luke</hi> 24. 16. ver. 37. 41. and twice he appeared in the midſt of them the Doors being ſhut, <hi>John</hi> 20. 19, 26. was there no Change then, as to his Body, from what it was before put to death, before which time he was alſo transfigured in the Mount, <hi>Mat.</hi> 17. 2. Thus the mighty Power of God appeared in his Change, after di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſe and wonderful manners, beyond the Reach of humane Capacity to comprehend, therefore to confine him now to <hi>the ſame Form and Figure</hi> is <hi>W. H.</hi> his Conceit and Im<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>gina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, wherein he intrudes into things he never ſaw. And as for his uncouth and unſcriptural Talk, that <hi>the Saints ought to wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip the Humane Nature of Chriſt, and that this humane Nature as ſuch as giveth Life unto our ſouls,</hi> p. 67. We need take little; notice of ſuch Language; Did not Chriſt ſay, <hi>I am the
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:101741:7"/>
Living Bread, which came down from Heaven; if any man ate of this Bread, he ſhall live forever; and the Bread which I will give, is my Fleſh, which I will give for the Life of the World,</hi> John 6. 51. for that his Fleſh that gives Life is himſelf.</p>
            <p>As for thoſe Objections againſt the Man Chriſt, <hi>his being in Heaven,</hi> in p. 8, 9. They are of <hi>W. Haworth</hi>'s own framing, and not the <hi>Quakers,</hi> however he would place them upon us, where in he hath dealt very diſingenuouſly and diſhoneſtly, and as a meer Forger: For where did the <hi>Quakers</hi> ever thus argue? viz. Object. <hi>The Apoſtle ſaith,</hi> Epheſ. 4. 10. <hi>That he aſcend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed far above all Heavens, therefore Chriſt is not in Heaven in his MANHOOD.</hi> Let him ſhew us that Book and Page of ours, or Diſpute, wherein we have this Argument or Objecti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, if he can. Again, When and where did ever the <hi>Quakers</hi> thus argue, viz. <hi>Chriſt ſaid to his Diſciples, I am with you al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>way, even to the End of the World,</hi> Mat. 28. 20 <hi>HOW THEN CAN HE BE IN HEAVEN?</hi> Let <hi>W. H.</hi> produce us that Book and Page of ours that hath this Inference in it, if he can; or elſe be aſhamed with ſuch Forgery to beſpatter us. Again, its ſaid 1 Cor. 15. <hi>Fleſh and Blood cannot enter unto the Kingdom of Heaven;</hi> where do the <hi>Quakers</hi> argue from hence that therefore <hi>Chriſt is not there, as to his Manhood?</hi> Let him produce Book and Page for this, or forever be aſhamed.</p>
            <p>His Reaſons to prove <hi>Chriſt now a Man in heaven,</hi> do not reach us nor touch us. the thing not being denyed, but really believed and confeſſed unto by us in the True, Spiritual and Scripture Senſe thereof; ſo that we have no need of his weak and confuſed Reaſons to convince us.</p>
            <p>And now farther to manifeſt, how like a Confuſed and Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtempered or Crazed Man <hi>W. H.</hi> writes, take a ſhort View of ſome of his Inconſiſtencies in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>is <hi>Poſtſcript</hi> againſt <hi>Chr. Taylor.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>C. T.</hi> having pleaded the Innocencv of Infants in the Womb, as not condemnable for the Sin of the firſt Parents, &amp;c. <hi>W. H.</hi> in his purſuing his Charge againſt all Infants, as having the <hi>Original Sin of the firſt</hi> Adam <hi>upon them that had not actually ſinned or tranſgreſſed,</hi> p. 17. wherein having ſhewed a great deal of Ignorance and Hardneſs, not worth our Labour to anſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer;
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:101741:8"/>
he citeth <hi>Epheſ.</hi> 2. 3. <hi>And were by Nature Children of Wrath;</hi> i. e. ſaith he, <hi>by Birth, Parent, Original, &amp;c. C. T.</hi> ſaying, <hi>They condemn the Innocent</hi> (that is, upon their Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deſtinarian Principle) To this <hi>W. H.</hi> reflects thus, viz. <hi>Let the Reader judge, if in this he writes not too much like an Inno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cent; but this is the Fruit of following the Light Within, and for ſaking the Scriptures: Nature will never diſcover its own Guilt and Deſilement; and the Light Within, that every man hath, is no more then Nature,</hi> pag. 17. See here how he makes no better account of the Light in man then of Corrupt Sinful Nature, making them both one, ſo putting no Diffe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rence between the Precious and the Vile. But in plain Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tradiction to this he confeſſeth, <hi>That the Scripture ſaith, this Light within every man is nothing but the Law of</hi> Moſes, <hi>writ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten in the Heart of Man,</hi> Rom. 2. 15. <hi>which ſhews the Work of the Law written in their Hearts,</hi> pag. 18. Do but ſee now how like a Mad Man he has written, one while to account the Light in man no more then Nature, which is ſinful, and by which men are Children of Wrath, and that the following thereof makes a man write like an Innocent (that is, an <hi>Idiot</hi> or <hi>Fool)</hi> when preſently after he is made to confeſs, <hi>That this Light in man is the Law of</hi> Moſes <hi>written in the Heart of Man.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Again, As he has manifeſted his Madneſs againſt the Light within, ſo he hath againſt the Works done by the Spirit of God; after he <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ath falſly accuſed the <hi>Quakers, of going about of ſet up their own Righteouſneſs,</hi> he proceeds thus, <hi>viz.</hi> on <hi>Rom.</hi> 4. 6. even as <hi>David</hi> alſo deſcribeth the Bleſſedneſs of the man unto whom God imputeth Righteouſneſs without Works; <hi>What Works? done by the Spirit ſurely</hi> (ſaith he) <hi>for ſuch were</hi> David's <hi>Works:</hi> And further proceeds, <hi>Did not</hi> Iſaiah <hi>obſerve</hi> Moſes's <hi>Law in the Spirit, and yet in that place of</hi> Iſaiah 64. 3. <hi>calls it filthy Raggs, as to Iuſtification? And did not</hi> Paul <hi>obſerve</hi> Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes's <hi>Law in the Letter and Spirit, when a</hi> Chriſtian? <hi>And he counted all things Loſs for the Excellency of the Knowledge of Ie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſus, and then ſurely his Obſervance of the Law of</hi> Moſes, <hi>in the spirit, in point of Iuſtification, this but his own Righteouſneſss,</hi> pag. 18. But pray read <hi>Paul</hi>'s own words, <hi>Phil.</hi> 3. 7, 8, 9.
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:101741:8"/>
Is it good Doctrine to ſay, <hi>That</hi> Paul, <hi>when</hi> Chriſtian, <hi>coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted his spiritual Obedience to the Law of God in spirit,</hi> Loſs <hi>and</hi> Dung <hi>for Chriſt,</hi> and that as a <hi>Chriſtian</hi> he muſt ſuffer the, <hi>Loſss of this</hi> ſo as <hi>not</hi> to have <hi>this inward or ſpiritual Obedience to the Righteous Law of God in his Heart?</hi> whereas <hi>Paul</hi> ſaith expreſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, <hi>The Law of the spirit of Life in Chriſt Ieſus hath made me free from the Law of ſin and Death,</hi> Rom. 8, 2.</p>
            <p>This Man cau ſet up Juſtification and Imputation at an eaſie rate, he can caſt the Law of the Spirit within behind his Back, and yet plead <hi>he is juſtified by the Imputation of Chriſt's Perſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal Righteouſneſs:</hi> O groſs Hypocriſie! whereas Chriſt <hi>came to condemn ſin in the Fleſh, that the Righteouſneſs of the Law might be fulfilled</hi> in us, <hi>who walk not after the Fleſh, but after the spirit,</hi> Rom. 8. 4. Yet this Preacher, <hi>W. H.</hi> confeſſeth, That <hi>that of Regeneration is the making one meet for the Inheritance of the Kingdom;</hi> and calls <hi>inherent Righteouſneſs the Righte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ouſneſs of the Law;</hi> and ſaith, <hi>That</hi> ALL <hi>the Righteouſneſss that the</hi> BEST <hi>of the Saints have</hi> WITHIN <hi>them or without them, is no more but the Righteouſneſss of the Law, by which we are not juſtified,</hi> pag. 19. having before told us, that <hi>Iſaiah's Obſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vance of</hi> Moſes'<hi>s Law in the spirit,</hi> he calls it <hi>filthy Rags;</hi> and <hi>Paul's Obſervance thereof, but his own Righteouſneſss,</hi> which he counted Loſs and Dung for Chriſt: and now, that ALL the Righteouſneſs <hi>that the Best of Saints have within them, is no more but the Righteouſneſs of the Law;</hi> that is, all that God and Chriſt has wrought in them, as their Regeneration, Sancti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fication &amp; Renewing in the Inner Man after the Image of God, and are but all a man's own Righteouſneſs, Loſs and Dung: and did ye ever read ſuch <hi>monſtrous diſtracted Doctrine</hi> as this? But to wheel about again, and to overturn all this at one heave, he confeſſeth, That <hi>it is the Actions of the Deity that perfects all Good for us and</hi> IN US, p. 7, 8. And in his <hi>Epiſtle Dedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>catory,</hi> prayes for his <hi>much honoured Friend</hi> thus, <hi>The Lord by his spirit eſtabliſh, ſettle, ſtrengthen you in this and every Truth, and preſerve you and your Elect Lady to his Heavenly Kingdom.</hi> Here he ſeems to eſteem highly of the Holy Spirit, and its in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward Work, how ſleight ſoever he hath made of it in other
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:101741:9" rendition="simple:additions"/>
places. But for his diſtracted and incongruous Works he hath provided this Salve in his <hi>Epiſtle,</hi> viz. <hi>Pray Sr. candidly bear with what may not be ſo congruouſly worded, in ſo ſublame a My<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtery;</hi> as alſo, that he <hi>is the leaſt and moſt unfit of his Brethren.</hi> Now if this man were really as humble as here he pretends, he would ſtudy to be quiet among his Neighbours, and not to concern himſelf in theſe Controverſies, which he is ſo incon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gruous and diſtempered in, and ſo unfit for the Mannagement of: And you that are his chief Hearers, would be his Friends, if you did perſwade him to Quietneſs, and not to trouble his weak Head with theſe Controverſies, laſt he fall into ſuch ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nifeſt Diſtraction as may tend to his and your great Reproach; for he appears in ſome Danger: and do not give him Money for endeavouring to keep you and Chriſt at a Diſtance, Revi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling the <hi>Quakers,</hi> and Undervaluing the Light Within, and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward Vertues and Operations of the Spirit of God.</p>
            <p>And as to his Boaſt, <hi>That to this day his whole Book is at our Door Unanſwered:</hi> We ſay, this is not ſtrictly True; for an <hi>Anſwer</hi> hath been writ to it a long time, but the Publicati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on deferred, partly for the ſame Reaſon he gives for <hi>C. Taylor</hi>'s Paper, viz. <hi>Counſel hath been given to ſletght it by Silence, as not being worthy an Anſwer, or particular Animadverſion.</hi> But if by his too much Boaſting and Clamour he occaſions its Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lication, it may not redound to his Credit, but he himſelf may have need of a better <hi>Antidote</hi> then yet he hath found out.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Hertford,</hi> 
                  <date>the 24th of the 5th Moneth, 1676.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
            <trailer>THE END.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:101741:9"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
